The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
VICTOR COSTAN: Hi, everyone.
维克多·科斯坦：大家好。
I am Victor.
我是维克多。
My full name is Victor Costan.
我的全名是Victor Costan。
I'm a third year Ph.D. student.
我是博士三年级。学生。
I'm in CSAIL, and I work in systems.
我在CSAIL，并且在系统中工作。
I do mostly security and distributed systems.
我主要负责安全性和分布式系统。
And I'll be your algorithm TA for this term.
我将担任本学期的算法助教。
Yay.
好极了。
How many people went to lecture yesterday?
昨天有多少人去听课？
All right.
好吧。
Are there any parts of the lecture that were particularly
讲座中是否有任何特别之处
unclear that you guys want to go over?
不清楚你们想过去吗？
So that I schedule what I talk about in such a way
这样我就可以安排我谈论的话题
that I'll cover that more than the parts
我将涵盖的范围不止于零件
that are boring and obvious.
很无聊，很明显。
AUDIENCE: Can you explain complexity in equations,
听众：您能解释方程式的复杂性吗？
because I took 042 like 3 years ago.
因为我像3年前一样拿了042。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
What else?
还有什么？
Thank you.
谢谢。
AUDIENCE: Maybe some basic outlines for, like,
听众：也许，
writing proofs relevant to like the [INAUDIBLE].
撰写与[音频不清晰]类似的证明。
VICTOR COSTAN: All right.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: Sort of methodology or something.
听众：某种方法论或其他东西。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Anything else?
还要别的吗？
OK.
好。
We're going to get started then.
然后我们将开始。
So the hardest, and I think most important of the whole course,
因此，在整个课程中，最难的也是最重要的，
is learning how to deal with asymptotic complexity.
正在学习如何处理渐近复杂性。
So asymptotic complexity is this very nice tool
因此，渐近复杂度是非常好的工具
where you have a function that looks
你有一个看起来像的功能
like this plus-- what'll I have here?
像这样加上-我在这里要吃什么？
10 plus sin x.
10加罪恶x。
So you have this guy, which is quite long and horrible
所以你有一个很长很恐怖的家伙
and would make your life miserable
会让你的生活痛苦
if you'd have to reason about it.
如果您必须对此进行推理。
And you can say that this is theta of n squared.
您可以说这是n平方的theta。
x, sorry.
x，对不起。
So everything that's here goes away.
因此，这里的所有内容都会消失。
And this constant factor here goes away,
这个恒定的因素消失了，
and it's nice and small function.
它的功能不错，功能也很小。
Why is that the case, first of all?
为什么会这样呢？
If I plot this function-- and since I don't have my projector
如果我绘制此功能-而且因为我没有投影机
you'll have to take my word for it--
您必须遵守我的承诺-
I will get something that looks like this.
我会得到这样的东西。
If I plug this function, I will get
如果插入此功能，我会得到
something that looks like this.
看起来像这样的东西。
This is a scale from 0 to 200.
这是从0到200的比例。
However, if I make my scale 0 to 20,000--
但是，如果我将刻度设为0到20,000，
Let's say 200,000 to make sure that is going to be correct.
假设有200,000个可以确保正确无误。
x squared looks like this.
x平方看起来像这样。
And this function looks like this.
这个函数看起来像这样。
And as you make the scale bigger and bigger,
随着规模的扩大，
you can't even see this noise anymore.
您甚至再也看不到这种噪音。
The reason is that all the noise is in this term.
原因是所有的噪音都在这个术语中。
In the x to the power of one fifth term.
在x中有五分之一的幂。
And as n-- pretend this is n, x, n same thing--
就像n-假装这是n，x，n一样-
so as the input to the function gets bigger and bigger,
因此，随着对函数的输入越来越大，
this grows at a much faster rate than this.
它以比这快得多的速度增长。
So if I don't care about this, how the function grows,
因此，如果我对此不关心，功能如何增长，
I can ignore anything aside from the dominant term.
除了主导词外，我什么都可以忽略。
Do people remember this from lecture?
人们在演讲中还记得吗？
Does this make sense?
这有意义吗？
OK.
好。
If it doesn't, that's great.
如果没有，那就太好了。
It means that I'm not wasting time covering it.
这意味着我不会浪费时间来解决它。
So we learned about three symbols,
因此，我们了解了三个符号，
or we will learn about three symbols,
否则我们将了解三个符号，
when talking about asymptotic complexity.
在谈论渐进复杂性时。
The three symbols are theta, O, and omega.
这三个符号分别是theta，O和omega。
Let's say this complicated function is g.
假设这个复杂的函数是g。
And this nice simple function is f.
这个简单的函数是f。
If I say that g of x is theta of f of x, that means two things.
如果我说x的g是x的f的theta，那意味着两件事。
It means I have a lower bound, like I showed here,
就像我在这里所示，这意味着我有一个下限，
and the lower bound looks something like x squared.
下界看起来像x平方。
And it means that I also have a higher-- an upper bound for it
这意味着我也有一个更高的上限
that also looks like x squared.
看起来也像x平方。
So the upper bound would be something like this.
因此，上限将是这样的。
And if I say this, then I'm making a promise
如果我这样说，那是我的承诺
that the function stays between the lower
该功能停留在较低
bound and the upper bound, and the bounds
界限和上限，以及界限
look sort of the same.
看起来差不多。
I can't really have x squared here, and x squared here.
我真的不能在这里x平方，在这里x平方。
Right?
对？
That would be impossible.
那是不可能的。
So that's why I said they look the same.
这就是为什么我说它们看起来相同。
They're not the same.
他们不一样。
And they're not the same, because they're
他们不一样，因为他们
allowed to differ by a constant factor.
允许相差一个常数。
So if this is f, and say this is f prime, f of x
因此，如果这是f，并说这是f素数，则x的f
might be x squared.
可能是x平方。
And we know for sure that this is going to be lower than this.
而且我们可以肯定的是，这将低于这个水平。
And f prime of x might be 1.2 times x squared.
x的f素数可能是x平方的1.2倍。
And because I have a 1.1 here-- and I
而且因为我在这里有一个1.1-我
know that these get smaller and smaller in relation to this
知道这些相对于此变得越来越小
as the function-- as the inputs to the function get bigger--
随着功能的发展-随着功能的投入越来越大-
I know that this is going to be the dominating factor.
我知道这将是主要因素。
And because this is bigger than this,
而且因为这比这个更大，
this function is going to eventually
该功能将最终
be larger than this function.
大于此功能。
So I have a bound from above, and I have a bound from below.
因此，我从上方有一个界限，而我从下方有一个界限。
And the bounds look almost the same.
边界看起来几乎相同。
They're only different by a constant factor.
它们仅相差一个常数。
This is theta.
这是θ。
To make things spicier-- by the way,
顺便说一句，让事情变得更有趣
theta is really hard to pronounce as opposed to O,
与O相反，theta确实很难发音，
so we usually say and write O instead of theta.
所以我们通常说O而不是theta
We'll talk about what O really means in a bit.
我们稍后将讨论O的真正含义。
But if you see O in a lot of places, including our notes,
但是，如果您在很多地方看到O，包括我们的笔记，
know that most of the time we actually mean theta.
知道大多数时候我们实际上是指theta。
And sorry for that.
对此深表歉意。
AUDIENCE: When do we you actually mean O?
听众：我们什么时候真正表示O？
VICTOR COSTAN: You can ask us, and we'll tell you.
维克多·科斯坦：您可以问我们，我们会告诉您。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
Fortunately, it doesn't a matter too much.
幸运的是，这没什么大不了的。
So we're trying to get an idea of how the functions look
因此，我们试图了解这些功能的外观
like in the bigger picture.
就像在大局中一样。
So most of the time it doesn't matter.
所以大多数时候都没关系。
I'll give you an example though of where it matters,
我会给你一个例子，说明它的重要性，
and how it could matter.
以及它可能有多重要。
So suppose I have another function that looks like this.
因此，假设我还有另一个看起来像这样的功能。
So this is kind of ugly, too.
所以这也很丑。
This function is g of x, say x times 1 plus sin of x.
该函数是x的g，例如x乘以1加x的sin。
So I can't say anything about the lower bound of this.
因此，我对此无能为力。
This is going to hit 0 at an infinite number of values.
这将以无限数量的值达到0。
Right?
对？
So I can't say that-- I can't have a nice lower bound for it.
所以我不能这么说-我不能为它设定一个很好的下限。
The lower bound for it is 0.
下限为0。
But I'm pretty sure that it's never
但我很确定永远不会
going to be bigger than 2x.
将大于2倍。
Right?
对？
And that's still worth something.
那还是值得的。
So there's this other function here
所以这里有另一个功能
that's supposed to be a line.
那应该是一条线。
Pretend it's a line.
假装这是一条线。
f of x equals 2x.
x的f等于2x。
And I know for sure that this is never
我可以肯定，这永远不会
going to exceed these, this.
将会超过这些。
And in that case, where I only have one upper bound,
在那种情况下，我只有一个上限，
and I don't have a good lower bound, I say that g of x
而且我没有很好的下界，我说x的g
is order of f of x.
是x的f的阶数。
And this is where-- This is what O really means.
这就是-这就是O的真正意思。
It means that I only have an upper bound and not
这意味着我只有一个上限，而没有
a lower bound.
下界。
In most of the cases when you're coding something,
在大多数情况下，当您编写代码时，
you don't really care how well your program
你真的不在乎你的程序有多好
can run if you're really lucky.
如果您真的很幸运，可以运行。
What you really care about is how does it
您真正关心的是如何进行
run in the worst case?
在最坏的情况下运行？
Or how does it run most of the time?
还是大多数情况下如何运行？
So suppose you're Google, and you're writing your search
因此，假设您是Google，并且您正在编写搜索
engine, and you have to return the result
引擎，您必须返回结果
to the user in 200 milliseconds.
在200毫秒内发送给用户。
Because they did a study that shows that if you return
因为他们进行的一项研究表明，如果您返回
the result in 400 milliseconds, they
结果以400毫秒为单位，
lose some number of users, which means
失去一些用户，这意味着
they lose some number of billions a year.
他们每年损失数十亿美元。
So to them a guarantee that their algorithms complete
因此对他们来说，保证他们的算法是完整的
in 200 milliseconds is pretty important,
在200毫秒内非常重要，
because it means a ton of money.
因为这意味着一大笔钱。
So if you have a running time that looks like this,
因此，如果您的运行时间看起来像这样，
that's OK, as long as this is 200 milliseconds
没关系，只要是200毫秒
for the number of pages that Google indexes.
Google索引的页面数。
Does that make sense?
那有意义吗？
OK.
好。
No answer means yes.
没有答案意味着是。
So if it doesn't make sense, please say something.
因此，如果没有任何意义，请说些什么。
OK, I will draw another function.
好的，我将绘制另一个功能。
Again--
再次 -
AUDIENCE: Victor?
听众：维克多？
VICTOR COSTAN: --wavy.
维克多·科斯坦：-波浪形。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: It says x times 1 plus something [INAUDIBLE].
听众：说x乘以1加[听不清]。
So what?
所以呢？
VICTOR COSTAN: So it's--
维克多·科斯坦：所以-
AUDIENCE: Oh it's sin.
听众：哦，这是罪过。
VICTOR COSTAN: 1 plus sin of x.
维克多·COSTAN：1加x的罪。
It--
它 -
AUDIENCE: It looks like [INAUDIBLE].
听众：看起来像[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: Yeah.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
Sorry, my handwriting is not very good.
抱歉，我的笔迹不是很好。
AUDIENCE: It's OK.
听众：可以。
Mine isn't either.
我的也不是。
VICTOR COSTAN: And it doesn't really
维克多·科斯坦：而且不是真的
matter what it is, it just needs to be sin
不管是什么，只需要犯罪
so that it looks wavy like this.
这样看起来像波浪形
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
VICTOR COSTAN: So that I can make
维克多·科斯坦：这样我就可以
something that looks complicated.
看起来很复杂的东西。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: Got it.
听众：知道了。
AUDIENCE: I have a question, too.
听众：我也有一个问题。
In the first example, is it 1.2 times x squared?
在第一个示例中，是否为x平方的1.2倍？
VICTOR COSTAN: Yes.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
I wanted something that's higher than 1.1.
我想要的东西高于1.1。
AUDIENCE: It's like [INAUDIBLE].
听众：就像[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: Yes.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
OK.
好。
Now that I got a break, does anyone else
现在我休息了，还有其他人吗
want to ask questions?
想问问题吗？
OK.
好。
So I'm going to draw another function.
所以我要画另一个功能。
This one looks like this.
这个看起来像这样。
And this is f of x equals 1 plus sin of x.
x的f等于1加x的sin。
I have to use these signs to make them look like that.
我必须使用这些标志使它们看起来像那样。
Times x to the power of-- What do I have there?
乘以x的力量-我在那里有什么？
1 5 plus x to the power of one fourth.
1 5加x为四分之一的幂。
So for this function I know for sure that it is greater than x
因此对于此函数，我肯定知道它大于x
to the power of one fourth.
达到四分之一的力量
Right?
对？
So if this is--
所以如果这是-
I know for sure that it's greater than that.
我肯定知道它比那还大。
Also if I look at this, and I know that sin is never
另外，如果我看着这个，我知道罪恶永远不会
bigger than 1, I know this whole thing is going to be,
大于1，我知道整个事情都会发生，
at most, 2.
最多2。
So if I have another function that
所以如果我有另一个功能
says f prime of x equals, say, 3 times x to the power of 1.5,
说x的f素数等于x的3乘以1.5的幂，
I know that it's going to bound it from above.
我知道它会从上面限制它。
So I have two bounds.
所以我有两个界限。
So it sort of looks like this case.
所以看起来像这种情况。
Except when I use theta, I have to make sure
除非我使用theta，否则我必须确保
that the bounds are very similar.
边界非常相似。
They can only differ by a constant factor.
它们只能相差一个常数。
In this case my bounds differ by the exponent
在这种情况下，我的界限因指数而异
here, which is more than a constant factor,
在这里，这不仅仅是一个常数，
so they're not the same.
所以他们不一样。
So if I take my function-- which by the way is g--
因此，如果我采用我的功能-顺便说一下，它是g-
if I want to say that g to the x is theta of something, I can't.
如果我想说x的g是某物的theta，我不能。
Because no matter what I put in here,
因为不管我在这里放什么
it's not going to be correct.
这是不正确的。
The lower bound is this, the upper bound is this.
下限是这个，上限是这个。
But what I can do is I can say that I know for sure that it
但是我能做的是可以肯定地说我知道
is theta of x to the power one fourth.
是x的幂的四分之一的θ。
And by the way I can also say that it
顺便说一句，我也可以说
is order of x to the power of one fifth.
是x的幂到五分之一的幂。
So if you have weird running times that looks like this,
因此，如果您的运行时间看起来很奇怪，
then you can only use O and omega.
那么您只能使用O和omega。
And with that being said, we will
话虽如此，我们将
use O for pretty much the rest of this course.
本课程的其余大部分时间都使用O。
And for most of the cases we'll use it to mean theta.
在大多数情况下，我们将使用它来表示theta。
Oh, by the way, these formulas look ugly and complicated,
哦，顺便说一下，这些公式看起来丑陋而复杂，
because I wanted the graphs to look complicated to illustrate
因为我希望图表看起来复杂起来以说明问题
the idea that asymptotic notation makes
渐进符号使
things look simpler.
事情看起来更简单。
In this course the running times that you'll be dealing with
在本课程中，您将要处理的运行时间
are all look like this.
都是这样子的
They will either be order 1, order log n, order n, order n
它们将是1阶，log n阶，n阶，n阶
log n, n ordered n squared.
对数n，n排序n的平方。
You might have one or two cases where you get something else,
您可能会遇到一两种情况，
but most of the time if you have something else
但是大多数时候如果你还有其他东西
coming out of your occurrence, it means you're doing it wrong.
从事件中脱颖而出，就意味着您做错了。
So nice tip to have.
很棒的提示。
And you can see that I already started doing it.
您会看到我已经开始这样做了。
I'm already using O instead of theta.
我已经在用O代替theta了。
So I guess I'm getting into the habit.
所以我想我正在养成这种习惯。
AUDIENCE: So why did you leave the theta one blank for g of x?
听众：那么，为什么对x的g保留theta一个空白？
VICTOR COSTAN: Because whatever I
维克多·科斯坦：因为无论我
put here is going to be wrong.
放在这里将是错误的。
If I put x to the power of one fifth,
如果我将x乘以五分之一的幂，
this is wrong, because I can have an upper bound that
这是错误的，因为我可以有一个上限
has x to the power of one fifth in it.
x的幂为五分之一。
But I can't have a lower bound like that,
但是我不能有这样的下限，
because this function hits x to the power of one
因为此函数使x达到1的幂
fourth in infinitely many points.
在无限多点中排名第四。
If I try to do x to the power of one fourth, same deal.
如果我尝试将x放大至四分之一的幂，则同样的处理。
Lower bound yes, upper bound no.
下限是，上限是。
So whatever I put in here is going to be wrong.
因此，无论我在此处输入什么内容，都会出错。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Good question.
好问题。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Is that 1.4 or one fourth?
听众：是1.4还是四分之一？
VICTOR COSTAN: 1.4.
维克多·波士坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：1.4。
They are 1.4 and 1.5
它们是1.4和1.5
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
Because I thought you were saying 1/4 and I was--
因为我以为你说的是​​1/4而我是-
VICTOR COSTAN: Oh, sorry.
维克多·科斯坦：抱歉。
1 4, 1.4.
1 4，1.4。
1.4, 1.5.
1.4、1.5。
OK.
好。
Are we good so far?
到目前为止我们还好吗？
OK.
好。
Let's go through a couple of exercises.
让我们进行一些练习。
So I'll give you a few functions-- Yes?
所以，我给您提供一些功能-是吗？
AUDIENCE: Do you make omega-- Is that-- It's
听众：你是欧米茄的吗-是的-是的
a lower bound already without multiplying by any constant,
下界已经没有乘以任何常数，
or something?
或者其他的东西？
Is that what it is?
那是什么吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: So for all of these,
维克多·科斯坦：所以对于所有这些，
what you put here is the simple, is the simple form.
您在这里输入的是简单形式，是简单形式。
So you're lower bound can be this function multiplied
因此您的下界可以乘以该函数
by any constant factor.
任何恒定的因素。
AUDIENCE: That-- So omega means lower bound?
听众：那-欧米茄意味着下界吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: Omega means lower bound,
维克多·科斯坦：欧米茄意味着下界，
O means upper bound, theta means both.
O表示上限，theta表示两者。
OK.
好。
Any other things to clear up before I ask questions?
在问问题之前还有其他需要清除的内容吗？
So it's your turn before it's my turn.
轮到你了，轮到我了。
All right.
好吧。
I'm going to go over a few functions,
我将介绍一些功能，
and I want you guys to tell me what--
我要你们告诉我什么
to help me write them in asymptotic notation.
帮我用渐近符号来写
So I will have f of n.
因此，我将得到f为n。
And I want to know it's theta of what?
我想知道这是什么的theta？
So let's start with f of n equals 10 to the 80.
因此，让我们从n的f等于80等于10开始。
Does anyone know why 10 to the 80?
有谁知道为什么10到80？
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: That'd be O of 1.
听众：那是1的O。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
That's the correct answer.
那是正确的答案。
You 're going ahead though.
不过，您正在前进。
I was wondering if-- I was wondering if you know why?
我想知道是否-我想知道你为什么吗？
Why did I choose this?
我为什么选择这个？
Does anyone know why I chose this?
有谁知道我为什么选择这个？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Is that [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：那是[听不清]？
VICTOR COSTAN: I think that's 100.
维克多·科斯坦：我认为是100。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK.
听众：哦，好。
VICTOR COSTAN: You're getting close though.
维克多·科斯坦：但是，你已经接近了。
It's something.
是的
AUDIENCE: It's a really big number.
听众：这是一个很大的数字。
VICTOR COSTAN: It's a really big number.
维克多·科斯坦：这是一个很大的数字。
All right.
好吧。
So it's a really big number.
所以这是一个很大的数字。
That's the estimated number of atoms in the universe.
那是宇宙中估计的原子数。
So realistically any quantity that you
几乎所有的数量
deal with that will represent the real world,
处理将代表现实世界，
is not going to be bigger than this.
不会比这个更大。
So if you want to get all philosophical,
因此，如果您想了解所有哲学知识，
you can say that for any algorithm that you write
您可以说，对于您编写的任何算法
in any realistic input the running time
在任何实际输入中运行时间
will be theta of 1.
将是1的θ。
But if you do this, we're not going to be happy with you
但是如果您这样做，我们将不会对您满意
on exams.
在考试中。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
So let's choose another one.
因此，让我们选择另一个。
20 n to the power of 7.
20 n至7的幂。
What's this an asymptotic notation?
这是一种渐近符号吗？
And why?
又为什么呢
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Order O of n to the seventh.
听众：n的O阶到第七。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Of that same thing, n to the seventh.
同样，n到第七。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Why is that?
这是为什么？
AUDIENCE: Because if you distribute the exponent 7,
听众：因为如果您分配指数7，
20 to the seventh is a constant.
20到第七是常数。
VICTOR COSTAN: Excellent.
VICTOR COSTAN：太好了。
20 to the 7 time n to the 7, this
20到7时间n到7
is a constant so it goes away.
是一个常数，所以它消失了。
OK.
好。
And before I do another one, I want
在我再做一个之前
to give you guys some help and remind you about logs.
给大家一些帮助，并提醒您有关日志的信息。
How many people remember the laws
有多少人记得法律
of working with logs from algebra or some math class?
来自代数或某些数学课的日志的方法？
All right.
好吧。
You guys will be helping me write them for everyone else.
你们会帮助我为其他人写的。
So if I have log of n to the 100,
因此，如果我的n的对数为100，
and I want to get to the theta notation for it, what is it
我想知道theta表示法是什么
and why?
为什么呢？
AUDIENCE: Log n.
听众：登录n。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Excellent.
优秀的。
Why is that the case?
为什么会这样？
AUDIENCE: It's 100 log n.
听众：100 log n。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So when I have an exponent here, I
所以当我在这里有指数时
can pull it out in front of the log as a constant factor.
可以将其作为恒定因子拉出日志的前面。
So this is the same thing as 100 log n.
因此，这与100 log n相同。
OK.
好。
Now if I have the logarithm to the base using base 5 of n--
现在，如果我使用n的以5为底的对数，
How about this?
这个怎么样？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] multiply.
听众：[听不清]相乘。
That's just log n?
那只是登录n？
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So this is-- can you say that again?
这是-您能再说一遍吗？
AUDIENCE: Log n.
听众：登录n。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So this is theta of log n because it is--
所以这是log n的theta，因为它是-
AUDIENCE: Log n over log 5.
听众：在日志5上登录n。
VICTOR COSTAN: So that's log n over log 5.
维克托·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：那是第5个日志n。
So exponents inside the logs turn into constant factors,
因此，原木内部的指数变成恒定因子，
bases turn into constant factors.
基础变成恒定因素。
So if you have an ugly expression inside a logarithm,
因此，如果对数中有一个丑陋的表达式，
you can, most of the time, simplify it
您大多数时候都可以简化它
to something really nice.
真的很棒
And this contributes to the fact that these
这有助于这些事实
are the only functions that you will see when the answer is
是答案时您将看到的唯一功能
cleaned up in asymptotic notation.
以渐近符号进行清理。
OK.
好。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: So when you're writing log,
听众：所以当您写日志时，
are you assuming the second base then?
那你是在假设第二个基地吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: Yes, there is a certain base for logs.
维克多·科斯坦：是的，有一定的日志基础。
We're all computer scientists.
我们都是计算机科学家。
Right?
对？
So what's the natural base for our logarithms?
那么对数的自然基础是什么？
AUDIENCE: 2.
听众：2。
2D.
2D
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Sweet.
甜。
Math major?
数学专业？
AUDIENCE: No, you know I always heard natural base--
听众：不，你知道我总是听自然的话-
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Yeah, it's a math joke.
是的，这是一个数学笑话。
So for everyone else a natural logarithm is in base E.
因此，对于其他所有人，自然对数位于E底。
For us CS people, a natural base is 2,
对于我们CS人士来说，自然基础是2
because that's how many values you have for a bit.
因为这就是您拥有多少个值。
So log means log n is to log base 2 of n.
因此log表示log n是以n为底的2。
The good news is that most of the time
好消息是，大多数时候
we're working with asymptotic notation,
我们正在使用渐近符号，
so it doesn't really matter.
所以这并不重要。
We can communicate with our math friends,
我们可以与数学朋友交流，
and we don't have to talk about this.
而且我们不必谈论这个。
OK.
好。
I need to get another complicated example.
我需要再举一个复杂的例子。
And my memory fails me.
我的记忆使我失望。
OK.
好。
So log-- See, I'm using Ln to mean the math
日志-看，我用Ln表示数学
natural logarithm.
自然对数。
So we still have that somewhere in here.
所以我们仍然在这里的某个地方。
Of log n to the base 100.
以n为底的log 100。
They made me add all these parentheses in the last section
他们让我在上一节中添加所有这些括号
to be clear, so I'm adding them now from the start.
清楚一点，所以我现在要从头开始添加它们。
Who wants to help me clean this up?
谁想帮我清理一下？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Log, log n.
听众：登录，登录n。
VICTOR COSTAN: All right.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Wow, one step.
哇，一步。
Log, log n OK.
登录，登录n确定。
Can you tell me why, very quickly?
你能很快告诉我为什么吗？
AUDIENCE: So we can simplify out the base and the exponent
听众：这样我们可以简化基础和指数
in there.
在那里。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: Then--
听众：然后-
VICTOR COSTAN: Base goes out.
维克多·科斯坦：基地出局了。
Exponent goes out.
指数消失。
AUDIENCE: Log, log of something is another [INAUDIBLE].
听众：日志，某物的日志是另一个[听不清]。
It's not exactly up there.
它不完全在那儿。
But can you--
但是你能-
VICTOR COSTAN: Yep.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
AUDIENCE: --occassionally [INAUDIBLE].
听众：-有时[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: Yep.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
What does a theory student say when they're drowning?
一个理论专业的学生在溺水时怎么说？
Log, log, log, log.
记录，记录，记录，记录。
Some of you are laughing already, because know this.
你们中有些人已经在笑，因为知道这一点。
OK.
好。
What if I want to make this a little bit harder?
如果我想加重一点该怎么办？
And I say log [INAUDIBLE] 5 of log n to the 100.
我说登录n的[听不清] 5到100。
You have to do a bit more work now,
您现在需要做更多的工作，
you can't just use the tricks on the right.
您不能只使用右侧的技巧。
Anyone else?
还有谁？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: It's still log, log n.
听众：它仍然是日志，请登录n。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
It is still log, log n.
它仍然是日志，日志n。
But for a different reason.
但是出于另一个原因。
Right?
对？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: Almost.
维克多·科斯坦：差不多了。
OK.
好。
Maybe not.
也许不吧。
So the base still goes out just like before.
因此，基地仍然像以前一样熄灭。
But this guy now goes out here.
但是这个家伙现在出去了。
So I will have this be, sort of like-- Notice
所以我会有这样的样子-注意
that I'm not saying equal, I'm saying
我不是说平等，我是说
like because I got rid of the base.
就像是因为我摆脱了基地。
So it's like 100 times log n, which is log 100 plus log,
就像100次log n，即log 100加log，
log n.
登录
And this is a constant factor, this grows as n grows.
这是一个常数，随着n的增加而增加。
So this is going to become incredibly small
所以这将变得非常小
as n becomes larger and larger, so I can get rid of it.
随着n变得越来越大，我可以摆脱它。
OK?
好？
OK.
好。
One more, and this one's going to be less boring.
再来一遍，这样就不会那么无聊了。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] out into a separate term-- the log of 100?
听众：[听不清]变成一个单独的词-对数100？
Going from it in the last step, how
在最后一步，如何
are you able to cross that out?
你能解决这个问题吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: If my memory-- If my memory works, I think,
维克多·科斯坦：如果我的记忆-如果我的记忆正常，
log of a b is log a plus log b.
ab的日志是log a加日志b。
AUDIENCE: Gotcha.
听众：Gotcha。
VICTOR COSTAN: Am I right guys?
维克多·科斯坦：我对吗？
Sweet.
甜。
Good question.
好问题。
I wasn't sure, but now that you asked,
我不确定，但是现在你问，
everyone else helped me make sure it's right.
其他所有人都帮助我确保它是正确的。
OK.
好。
I'm erasing so much, because we're
我擦除的太多了，因为我们
going to need more room for this.
为此需要更多空间。
So I have a log again, but this time what I have inside the log
所以我又有了一个日志，但是这次我的日志里面有什么
is n choose n over 2.
是n在2中选择n。
Does any brave soul want to come up here and solve this for me?
是否有任何勇敢的灵魂想来这里为我解决这个问题？
No?
没有？
You guys are going to make me write for the entire hour?
你们要让我整整写一遍吗？
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
VICTOR COSTAN: I'll offer help.
维克多·科斯坦：我会提供帮助。
AUDIENCE: It's n-- [INAUDIBLE]
听众：n-- [听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: So this is--
维克多·科斯坦：这就是-
AUDIENCE: Is that n factorial over --
听众：那是阶乘-
VICTOR COSTAN: Yep.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
AUDIENCE: --n divided by 2 factorial?
听众：--n除以2阶乘？
VICTOR COSTAN: n factorial over n divided by 2 factorial,
VICTOR COSTAN：n阶乘n阶除以2阶乘，
times n divided by 2 factorial.
n乘以2阶乘
Close.
关。
And I'll give up another hint, which
我将放弃另一个提示，
is that n factorial can be approximated
是n阶乘可以近似吗
as square root of 2pi n multiplied by n over E divided
作为2pi n的平方根乘以E上的n除
by n to the power of n.
由n乘以n的幂。
But I think this will make you guys not
但是我认为这会让你们不
want to come up and solve this.
想要解决这个问题。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: OK. [INAUDIBLE].
听众：好的。 [听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: I was-- Is that it?
维克多·科斯坦：我是-是吗？
Is that not it?
是不是
Did I get it wrong?
我弄错了吗？
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] minus n.
听众：[听不清]减n。
VICTOR COSTAN: I think that's an asymptotic.
维克多·科斯坦：我认为这是渐近的。
That's what we'll-- I think we'll get to that.
那就是我们要做的-我认为我们会做到的。
But factorials grow exponentially.
但是阶乘以指数级增长。
So it should be something like this.
所以应该是这样的。
OK.
好。
So we have that nice approximation.
因此，我们有一个很好的近似值。
Does anyone want to work it out, or will I have to do it?
是否有人想解决这个问题，还是我必须做？
I'll keep that in mind when I'm grading your homework.
在为您的作业评分时，我会记住这一点。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So it's log of square root 2 pi n multiplied by n over 2
就是平方根2 pi n乘以2上的n的对数
to the power of n.
达到n的幂
I'm going to put these two together.
我将把这两个放在一起。
So 2 pi n over-- There's an n over 2 there, right?
所以2点以上-那里2点以上，对吧？
So it's n over 2E times n over 2 to the power of 2.
因此，n是2E乘以n 2乘以2的幂。
OK, I can get rid of this guy, because it's a constant.
好吧，我可以摆脱这个家伙，因为它是一个常数。
I can get-- No, I can't get rid of this guy yet.
我可以-不，我还不能摆脱这个家伙。
AUDIENCE: In the denominator shouldn't it be 2pi n over 2
听众：分母不应该是2分以上2分
under the radical?
在激进之下？
VICTOR COSTAN: Yep.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
2pi n over 2, so this simplifies.
2分2分以上，因此简化了。
OK.
好。
Thank you.
谢谢。
AUDIENCE: Square at the bottom term,
观众：最底端的方块，
you can get rid of the square root on the end--
您可以摆脱最后的平方根-
VICTOR COSTAN: Yep.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
AUDIENCE: --and then cancel the some of the exponents.
听众：-然后取消一些指数。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Do you want to come help me?
你想来帮我吗
AUDIENCE: Sure.
听众：好的。
VICTOR COSTAN: Thanks so much.
维克多·科斯坦：非常感谢。
STUDENT: OK.
学生：好的。
So we can distribute this exponent here to cancel this.
因此，我们可以在此处分配该指数以取消该指数。
And then we get square root of pi n times n over 2.
然后我们得到pi的平方根乘以n等于2。
And it'd be n-- sorry about my handwriting.
抱歉-我的笔迹。
VICTOR COSTAN: I think it's better than mine
维克多·科斯坦：我认为这比我的要好
by quite a bit.
相当多。
STUDENT: Square root of pi n.
学生：pi的平方根。
And this is square root squared, so that cancels .
这是平方根平方，因此可以取消。
Times n over E to the n.
将E上的n乘以n。
AUDIENCE: Do you need parenthesis around n over 2E?
听众：您是否需要在2E上加上n左右的括号？
STUDENT: Yeah.
学生：是的。
That's probably good.
那可能很好。
So, since this is n over E to the n, and n over 2E n.
因此，由于这是E之上的n到n之上，而n是2E n之上。
Well since they're to the n, both the
好吧，既然他们到了n，
n we can give them a single exponent and cancel stuff.
n我们可以给他们一个指数并取消它们。
So we just get square root of pi n to the times 2
所以我们将pi n的平方根乘以2
the n, over pi n.
n，超过pi n。
Can do some more cancelling and just get 2 the n over--
可以做更多的取消，只得到2 n
Going to simplify this to the n over the square root of n.
将其简化为n的平方根上的n。
We can take out the pi, because it's in our natural logarithm.
我们可以删除pi，因为它在我们的自然对数中。
It's a constant factor.
这是一个恒定的因素。
And this is log of-- and then-- Since it's a log of,
这是-的日志-然后-因为是
it's just log of 2 to the n.
它是2到n的对数。
So it's-- say since it's log you can turn it into log of 2
所以-说，因为它是对数，您可以将其变成2的对数
to the n minus log of square root of n.
到n减去n的平方根的对数。
Log of 2 to the n is a much greater complexity
2到n的对数要复杂得多
than square root of n, so we can--
而不是n的平方根，所以我们可以-
VICTOR COSTAN: Sweet.
维克多·科斯坦：甜。
Thank you.
谢谢。
So see?
看到了吗
Complicated formula-- Even more complicated formula
复杂的公式-甚至更复杂的公式
came out to be one of the numbers
成为其中之一
that I promised it would come out to.
我保证会出来的。
Thanks for the help.
谢谢您的帮助。
So you can get rid of the pi as soon as you want to.
因此，您可以根据需要尽快删除pi。
And this is the last step.
这是最后一步。
I just want to say it again, just
我只想再说一次
make sure everyone heard it.
确保所有人都听到了。
So once you get here, you get this,
所以一旦到达这里，就得到了
order n minus log of square root of n,
阶n减去n的平方根的对数，
which is-- This is-- This is order n minus one half log n.
这是-这是-这是n阶乘以log n的一半。
And the log n is much smaller than n,
日志n远小于n，
so this goes away completely.
所以这完全消失了。
And you get this as your final answer.
而您得到的这就是您的最终答案。
OK.
好。
Does this make sense?
这有意义吗？
Any questions?
任何问题？
Anyone?
任何人？
How many people are still paying attention honestly?
多少人仍在诚实地关注？
Wow.
哇。
Nice.
真好
You should come to all my sections.
您应该参加我所有的部分。
OK.
好。
Let's talk about something we covered in class.
让我们谈谈我们在课堂上讨论的内容。
Let's talk about peak finding.
让我们谈谈寻峰。
And we'll start with 1D peak finding,
我们将从一维峰发现开始，
and then we'll go to 2D peak finding.
然后我们将进行2D峰发现。
So does anyone remember the pseudocode for the faster 1D
有人会记住更快的1D伪代码吗
peak finding by any chance?
找峰吗？
ID peak finding.
ID峰发现。
I think everyone said they went to lecture,
我想每个人都说他们去听课了，
so I don't have to explain what peak finding is, right?
所以我不必解释什么是峰值发现，对吗？
OK.
好。
So that's go for it.
这样就可以了。
So suppose I have a few numbers--
所以假设我有几个数字
3-- let me write this one-- 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 6, 5, 4.
3-让我写这个-3、4、5、6、7、6、5、4
So the peak finding problem says there's an array of numbers,
因此，寻峰问题表明其中存在一系列数字，
and I want to find the local peak.
我想找到当地的山峰
And the local peak is a number that's
而当地的高峰是
surrounded by numbers that are smaller or equal to it.
用小于或等于它的数字包围。
So there shouldn't be any larger numbers than it.
因此，不应有比它大的数字。
And I want to find a peak as quickly as I can.
我想尽快找到一个高峰。
So what's the faster algorithm that we talked about
那么我们所说的更快的算法是什么
in lecture?
在演讲中？
Yes?
是？
OK.
好。
You didn't answer, right, as much, at least so.
至少，您没有回答，对，至少如此。
AUDIENCE: Binary search?
受众：二进制搜索？
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
It's exactly like binary search.
就像二进制搜索一样。
Yep.
是的
Do you wanna help me write the pseudocode?
您想帮助我编写伪代码吗？
You can tell me what it is.
你可以告诉我这是什么。
AUDIENCE: Sure.
听众：好的。
So, I guess well start in the middle.
所以，我想从中间开始。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Start in the middle.
从中间开始。
If you-- If you write this on your Pset
如果您-如果将其写在Pset上
you might want to be a little bit more formal.
您可能想要更正式一点。
Someone asked about proofs.
有人问证据。
I would say something like, start
我会说开始
by looking at the middle element of the array.
通过查看数组的中间元素。
Same thing though.
虽然一样。
OK.
好。
So let's pretend this is the middle.
因此，让我们假装这是中间的。
Now it is.
现在它是。
What do I do?
我该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Then you can check one side in the middle.
听众：然后您可以检查中间的一侧。
So it's [INAUDIBLE] the right side.
因此，它在[音频不清晰]右侧。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
I'm looking at the right side.
我在看右边。
I see a 7 there, so I know for sure
我在那里看到7，所以我肯定知道
that this is not a local peak.
这不是本地高峰。
Right?
对？
What do I do now?
现在我该怎么做？
AUDIENCE: So now you can start over, and using 7.
听众：现在您可以重新开始并使用7。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
What if-- This would be small.
如果-那会很小。
What if I would look at 5 first?
如果我先看5怎么办？
Or you should I look at the other side too?
还是我也应该看看另一侧？
AUDIENCE: Well you don't have to in this case, but if you--
听众：嗯，在这种情况下您不必这样做，但是如果您-
But if 7 were smaller then you would
但是如果7小一些
go and look at the other side, and check
去看看另一边，然后检查
to see if 5 is also smaller.
看看5是否也更小。
In that case you've already found the peak.
在那种情况下，您已经找到了顶峰。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So I have to look at both sides and make sure-- if none of them
因此，我必须审视双方，并确保-如果没有一个
is smaller, than I-- I'm sorry.
比我小-对不起。
If none of them is bigger, I found the peak.
如果没有一个更大，我就找到了顶峰。
If any of them is bigger then I can go whichever way I want.
如果其中任何一个更大，那么我可以按照自己想要的方式走。
So I saw my 7, I'm going to cut this in half.
所以我看到了我的7，我将其切成两半。
And now I look at this.
现在我看看这个。
You were saying, right?
你是说吧
So look at the neighbors-- By the way,
所以看看邻居-顺便说一句，
can anyone understand my handwriting?
谁能理解我的笔迹？
Is it even worth bothering to write?
还要值得去写吗？
AUDIENCE: It's pretty good.
听众：很好。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
I see three nods.
我看到三个点头。
I'm going to write for those three people.
我要为那三个人写信。
AUDIENCE: It's just we haven't taken
听众：只是我们还没拿
any cursive in about 12 years.
在大约12年内可以找到任何草书。
So--
所以 -
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Not feeling well at all.
一点都不舒服。
OK look at neighbors, figure out if you're a peak.
好看看邻居，弄清楚你是不是高峰。
You're one of the people that said you can read it,
您是可以阅读的人之一，
so now there's only two people that can read my handwriting
所以现在只有两个人可以阅读我的笔迹
and that I like.
而且我喜欢。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
VICTOR COSTAN: Look at the neighbors.
维克多·科斯坦：看看邻居。
See if local peak.
看看是否有本地高峰。
And if not, figure out which way to go in.
如果没有，请弄清楚该走哪条路。
And I'll say if not recurse.
我会说如果不递归的话。
So what's the running time for this?
那么，这是什么时间？
Suppose I have n elements to start with,
假设我有n个元素开始，
that's my array size.
那是我的数组大小。
I will use t of n as my running time.
我将使用n的t作为我的跑步时间。
So to figure out the running time for the whole algorithm,
因此，要弄清楚整个算法的运行时间，
I have to look at the running time for each step
我必须查看每个步骤的运行时间
and add them up.
并将它们加起来。
Right?
对？
What's the running time for the first step?
第一步的运行时间是多少？
Looking in the middle.
看着中间。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] the middle elements.
听众：[听不清]中间元素。
VICTOR COSTAN: 1.
维克多·科斯坦：1。
1.
1。
I would not say 0.
我不会说0。
I still have to look at it.
我还是要看。
Or to be on the safe side you say 1, theta of 1.
或为了安全起见，您说1，theta。
It's a constant.
这是一个常数。
OK.
好。
Now I have to look at the neighbors,
现在我要看看邻居
and I have to see if one of them is bigger or not.
我必须看看其中一个是否更大。
How about that?
那个怎么样？
How much time is left?
还剩多少时间？
I heard the constant.
我听到了不断。
OK.
好。
Very soft voice, but I heard a constant there,
声音很柔和，但我听到那里常有声音，
so I'm going to take it.
所以我要接受它。
So this guy is a constant.
所以这个家伙是一个常数。
If it's a local, if you come down.
如果是当地人，那就下来吧。
If it's not a local peak, what's the running time for this?
如果不是本地高峰，那么运行时间是多少？
n over 2, since--
n大于2，因为-
AUDIENCE: If you FOIL that you divide by [INAUDIBLE], right?
听众：如果您觉得自己被[音频不清晰]除以对，对吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: Yep.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
So I'm looking at this guy.
所以我在看这个人。
It's clearly not a peak.
显然这不是高峰。
So I'm going to look on the right side,
所以我要看右边
because I see a 7 here that's bigger than a 6.
因为我看到这里的7比6大。
So now I have the same problem, except my array size just
所以现在我有同样的问题，除了我的数组大小
dropped to half.
下降到一半。
So same problem, because I already have a name for it,
同样的问题，因为我已经有个名字了，
except the input size is different.
除了输入大小不同。
So the running time for this entire step is theta of 1
因此，整个步骤的运行时间为1
plus T of n over 2.
加T大于2。
So the running time for the whole thing
所以整个事情的运行时间
is-- I should have said theta of 1 here, sorry.
是-我应该在这里说1的theta，对不起。
So theta of 1 plus theta of 1 plus T of n over 2.
所以1的theta加上1的theta加上n的T超过2。
So this is theta 1 plus T of n over 2.
所以这是theta 1加上n在2之上的T
So I wrote out my pseudocode, looked
所以我写了我的伪代码，看着
at the running time for each step, added them up.
在每个步骤的运行时间，将它们加起来。
Now I have a recurrence, and I have to solve it.
现在我复发了，我必须解决它。
Let's solve it.
让我们解决它。
We sort of glossed over that in lectures,
我们在演讲中对此有所掩饰，
so we're going to do it now.
所以我们现在就要做。
So T of n equals theta of 1 plus T of n over 2.
因此，n的T等于1的theta加上2上的n的T。
I'm going to expand this using the definition.
我将使用定义对此进行扩展。
And theta of one is long, so I'm going to call this c instead.
而且一个的theta很长，所以我改称它为c。
It's a constant, right?
这是一个常数，对吗？
So c plus-- expanding this-- c plus T of n over 4.
所以c加-扩展-c加n的T超过4。
I'm going to expand it again.
我将再次对其进行扩展。
And again-- Anyone getting bored of this?
再说一遍，有人对此感到无聊吗？
So if I expand it a lot of times, I'm going to get i times
所以如果我扩展很多次，我会得到很多次
c, plus T of n divided by 2 to the n.
c，n的T加2除以n。
And you can expand it as many times
您可以扩展多次
as you want until we see the pattern,
根据您的意愿，直到我们看到图案，
but this is the pattern.
但这是模式。
So I have a recurrence.
所以我复发了。
What else do I need in order to get a function?
我还需要什么才能获得功能？
I need a base case.
我需要一个基本案例。
So the problem size gets smaller and smaller and smaller,
因此问题的大小越来越小，
but at some point it becomes so small
但在某个时候它变得很小
that I can solve it just by looking at it.
我只要看一下就能解决。
What's that case?
那是什么情况
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So if I have an array of one element, it's a peak.
因此，如果我有一个元素的数组，那是一个峰值。
Right?
对？
Job done.
任务完成。
So T of 1 is a constant.
因此T等于1是一个常数。
So I want to write this in such a way that this becomes this.
所以我想以这样的方式来写这个。
So I want to figure out an i such that-- Yeah.
所以我想找出一个这样的-是的。
T of n divided by 2 to the i equals T of 1.
n的T除以2等于i等于T的1。
And the easiest way of doing that is
最简单的方法是
to say that n divided by 2 to the i is 1.
说n被2除以i是1。
So i is the inverse of an exponential-- Anyone?
所以我是指数的倒数-任何人？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: Logarithm, thank you.
维克多·科斯坦：对数，谢谢。
Log n.
登录n。
So I have i, and I'm going to plug it back in here.
所以我有我，我要把它重新插入这里。
And I get constant times log n, plus T of 1, which I know
我得到常数乘以log n，加上T等于1，我知道
is theta of 1.
是1的θ。
I'm going to make this theta of 1 again.
我将再次使这个θ为1。
So theta of 1 times log n, plus theta of 1.
所以1的theta的对数n加1的theta
And I know that log n dominates a constant,
而且我知道log n占主导地位，
so this is going to be theta of log n.
所以这将是log n的θ。
Solved.
解决了。
OK.
好。
How are we doing?
我们怎么样
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: In the second to last from the bottom,
观众：从倒数第二倒数第二，
I don't understand [INAUDIBLE] of c times log n
我听不清c次登录n的[听不清]
replace i by log n.
用日志n替换我。
In the second part of the equation, how did you--
在等式的第二部分中，您如何-
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So in the jump from here to here, where I said
所以在从这里跳到这里，我说
i equals log n-- Right?
我等于log n-对吗？
AUDIENCE: Yep.
听众：是的。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So i becomes log n, c stays c.
因此，我成为log n，c停留在c。
You're wondering about this part, right?
您想知道这部分，对吗？
So if i is log n, then 2 to the i is n.
因此，如果i为log n，则2等于i。
So I have T of 1, which I have here.
所以我的T为1，我在这里。
So I want this to have this happen.
所以我希望这种情况能够发生。
When I'm solving for i here, I set this guy to my base case,
当我在这里为我求解时，我将此人设置为基本情况，
so that I can get this to happen.
这样我才能做到这一点。
The idea here is that you're expanding the recursion
这里的想法是您正在扩展递归
forever, and you know that at some point
永远，你知道在某个时候
you're going to have to stop.
您将不得不停止。
When do you stop?
你什么时候停下来
You stop at the base case.
您停在基本情况下。
So you force this to become the base case.
因此，您迫使它成为基本案例。
OK?
好？
OK.
好。
Let's do 2D peak finding.
让我们进行2D峰发现。
Let's talk about it a little bit.
让我们谈一点。
So 2D peak finding is exactly like 1D peak finding,
因此2D峰发现与1D峰发现完全一样，
except you have a 2D matrix instead of a 1D array.
除了您使用2D矩阵而不是1D数组。
Let's see if I can do this right.
让我们看看我是否可以正确执行此操作。
So suppose this is our matrix.
因此，假设这是我们的矩阵。
And suppose these are the rows.
并假设这些是行。
Suppose we have m rows and n columns.
假设我们有m行n列。
Can anyone remind me what the psuedocode for 2D
谁能提醒我2D伪码是什么
peak finding that we talked about in lecture?
我们在讲座中谈到的高峰发现？
So we had two attempts.
因此我们进行了两次尝试。
The first one was a clear failure.
第一个显然是失败的。
It didn't work.
没用
The second one worked.
第二个工作。
And we talked about its running time a little bit.
我们还谈到了它的运行时间。
And then [INAUDIBLE] asked you to think of a variation
然后[听不清]让您考虑一个变化
to the second one.
到第二个。
So let's do those straight up second version
所以让我们直接做第二版
of the pseudocode without the variation.
没有变化的伪代码。
So 2D peak finding.
因此2D峰发现。
What is the algorithm?
什么是算法？
All right.
好吧。
One person was not asleep in my section at the end of lecture.
讲座结束时，我所在的区域没有一个人在睡觉。
I'm proud.
我很自豪。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
Well, Which one of us?
好吧，我们中的哪一个？
We both spoke at the same time.
我们俩同时讲话。
VICTOR COSTAN: You had your hand up first though.
维克多·科斯坦：虽然您首先举起了手。
AUDIENCE: So you just pick a middle of the column.
听众：因此，您只需选择列中间。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
And then you find the peak there.
然后您在那找到了顶峰。
AUDIENCE: And then you shift the neighbors, I think.
听众：我想，然后你转移邻居。
VICTOR COSTAN: Find peak neighbors.
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：查找高峰邻居。
AUDIENCE: Neighbors in the same room?
听众：邻居在同一个房间？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, yeah.
听众：是的，是的。
VICTOR COSTAN: That's the horizontal line, right?
维克多·科斯坦：那是水平线，对吧？
OK.
好。
So what do you mean by find the peak here?
那么，在这里找到峰值意味着什么？
AUDIENCE: Like within the column?
听众：喜欢在专栏中？
VICTOR COSTAN: Yes.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
So find the peak using what we talked about before?
因此，使用我们之前讨论的内容找到高峰吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Find 1D peak.
找到一维峰。
So you're thinking ahead.
所以您正在考虑。
You're thinking of the variation that [INAUDIBLE]
您正在考虑[音频不清晰]
asked you guys to think about at home.
让你们在家考虑。
I'm glad you thought about it.
很高兴您想到了。
That's good.
那很好。
But what's the one that we had in lecture?
但是我们讲座中有什么？
I don't want to think about-- I don't
我不想考虑-我不想
want to give you guys the answer yet.
想要给你们答案。
So what did we say we were going to do in lecture?
那我们说我们要在演讲中做什么？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: I think we just picked a spot,
观众：我想我们只是选了一个位置，
checked the neighbors and kept walking uphill.
检查邻居，并继续走上坡路。
That makes sense.
那讲得通。
Every time we found a neighbor that was bigger,
每当我们找到一个更大的邻居时，
we moved to that spot.
我们搬到那个地方。
Checked its neighbors.
检查了它的邻居。
VICTOR COSTAN: So this is the-- This
维克多·科斯坦：这就是
is the first algorithm that's slow.
是第一个速度很慢的算法。
It works.
有用。
You're going to get the correct answer.
您将得到正确的答案。
But it's slow because if you have some handily crafted
但这很慢，因为如果您有一些手工制作
matrix you can go like this, and you're basically
矩阵可以像这样去，基本上
going through the whole matrix.
遍历整个矩阵。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: I think there's like an algorithm that's
听众：我认为有一种算法
find a-- look through the column for its maximum,
找到-查看该列的最大值，
and then look to either side.
然后看向任一侧。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So instead of finding a 1D peak, we're
因此，我们没有找到一维峰，而是
going to find the maximum value.
要找到最大值。
OK.
好。
And this is correct, and let's look at its running time.
这是正确的，让我们看一下它的运行时间。
Does anyone want to help me?
有人想帮助我吗？
So this is T of n m.
因此，这是n m的T。
Right?
对？
Then rows, then columns.
然后是行，然后是列。
So what's the running time for the first step?
那么第一步的运行时间是多少？
Come on.
来吧。
This is the easy one.
这很容易。
Yes?
是？
The constant.
常数。
Perfect.
完善。
OK.
好。
What's the running time for finding
查找的运行时间是多少
a maximum amount of n numbers?
最多n个数字？
AUDIENCE: n.
听众：
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Perfect.
完善。
And suppose we do that here?
假设我们在这里这样做？
Suppose these rows don't exist.
假设这些行不存在。
Suppose this is my entire matrix.
假设这是我的整个矩阵。
And I'm here, and I found the maximum.
我在这里，我找到了最大的。
What do I do?
我该怎么办？
I look left, I look right.
我向左看，我向右看。
If both of them are smaller, then it
如果两者都较小，则
means I found my peak, because I know
表示我找到了自己的巅峰，因为我知道
that number was a maximum in my column.
这个数字是我专栏中的最大值。
Now if that's not the case, if I find a number that's bigger,
现在如果不是这样，如果我发现一个更大的数字，
I'll go in that direction.
我会朝那个方向走。
Does that sound reasonable?
听起来合理吗？
OK.
好。
So maximum for my column, and I'm going to go right.
因此，对于我的专栏文章，最大值是正确的。
So check neighbors, and I have the same two conditions there.
因此，请检查邻居，我在那里有两个相同的条件。
If it's a peak, then I'm happy.
如果是高峰，那我很高兴。
Otherwise recurse.
否则递归。
So what's the running time if I have to recurse?
那么，如果我必须递归的话，运行时间是多少？
How does the new problem look like?
新问题看起来如何？
It's an identical problem.
这是一个相同的问题。
I still have a matrix, except-- What changed?
我仍然有一个矩阵，除了-发生了什么变化？
So suppose I got here-- and this is the middle of my matrix--
所以假设我来到这里-这是矩阵的中间部分-
and I see that this guy is bigger,
我看到这个家伙更大，
so I'm going to recurse to the right side.
所以我要递归到右侧。
What happened to my problem size?
我的问题大小发生了什么？
OK?
好？
AUDIENCE: Sorry I'm not answering your question,
听众：对不起，我没有回答你的问题，
but shouldn't find x be theta of m, not n?
但是不应该发现x是m的theta，而不是n？
Is that [INAUDIBLE]?
那是[听不清]吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: Let me see.
维克多·科斯坦：让我看看。
AUDIENCE: I can't tell
听众：我不知道
VICTOR COSTAN: You are right.
维克多·科斯坦：对。
Thank you for paying attention.
感谢您的关注。
Theta m.
塞塔米
Sweet.
甜。
That would have tripped me up later.
那会在以后使我绊倒。
Thanks for saving me.
谢谢你救了我
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
So what was your question?
那你的问题是什么？
Sorry.
抱歉。
VICTOR COSTAN: So the question is, if I have to recurse--
COSTAN COSTAN：所以问题是，如果我必须递归-
AUDIENCE: Uh-huh.
听众：嗯。
VICTOR COSTAN: --what's the running time?
维克多·科斯坦：-几点钟了？
So I'm-- If I have to recurse, I'm in this array that was
所以我-如果必须递归，我在这个数组中
originally n by m, and I'm only going to look at the right
原本是n x m，我只看右边
side.
侧。
How many these-- how many rows do I have in the [INAUDIBLE]?
这些[我听不清]中有几行？
Start to the easy one.
从简单开始。
AUDIENCE: m.
听众：m。
VICTOR COSTAN: All right.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Same as before.
和之前一样。
How many columns?
多少列？
AUDIENCE: n over 2.
观众：超过2分。
VICTOR COSTAN: n over 2.
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：n大于2。
Sweet.
甜。
So there recursion for this is theta of 1
所以这个递归是1的theta
plus theta of m plus T of n over 2 and m.
加上m的theta加上n在2和m上的T。
I know that a constant can be absorbed by this other guy,
我知道另一个人可以吸收一个常数，
so it's theta of m plus T of n over 2 m.
所以它是m加上2 m的n的T的θ。
How would I solve this?
我该如何解决？
What's the first thing that we need?
我们需要的第一件事是什么？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Need to figure out the base case.
听众：需要弄清楚基本情况。
VICTOR COSTAN: All right.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Excellent.
优秀的。
Base case.
基本情况。
What's the best-- What was the base case?
最好的是-基本情况是什么？
AUDIENCE: T of 1 comma T of n-- m.
听众：n的1个逗号的T – m。
Sorry.
抱歉。
VICTOR COSTAN: Nice.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: Equal to O of m.
听众：等于m的O。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Sweet.
甜。
So if I only have one column, then I
因此，如果我只有一栏，那么我
can do-- I can find the maximum and I know for sure
可以做到-我可以找到最大值，并且我肯定知道
that's going to be a peak.
那将是一个高峰。
Job done.
任务完成。
That's my base case.
那是我的基本情况。
So I'm going to reduce the problem size in half,
所以我将问题的大小减少一半，
until I get to a single column.
直到我进入一个专栏。
Then I find the peak there, and I'm happy.
然后我在那找到了顶峰，我很高兴。
How would I solve this recurrence?
我该如何解决这种复发？
It's a one minute answer, because I
一分钟的答案，因为我
think that's exactly how much time we have, as a hint.
认为这正是我们有多少时间。
Come on guys, this looks familiar.
伙计们，这看起来很熟悉。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE:Going to be something like the recurrence over
听众：会像复发一样
there--
那里 -
VICTOR COSTAN: Exactly.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] of just n.
听众：[听不清]仅n。
VICTOR COSTAN: Exactly.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
m never changes, right?
我永远都不会改变，对吗？
So this is basically a function of n.
因此，这基本上是n的函数。
So if m never changes, and I pretend that it's a constant,
因此，如果m永远不变，我假装这是一个常数，
this looks exactly like the recursion-- the recurrence
这看起来完全像递归-递归
that we solve before.
我们之前解决过的。
T of n is a constant, plus T of n over 2.
n的T是常数，加上n的T大于2。
So I'm going to get that constant,
所以我要保持不变，
multiply it by log n, which is the solution that I had before.
将它乘以log n，这就是我以前的解决方案。
So the running time is theta of m log n.
因此，运行时间为m log n的theta。
All right.
好吧。
I think I have 30 seconds, so what if I would choose-- What
我想我有30秒，所以如果我选择-该怎么办？
if I would try to do this algorithm instead?
如果我想尝试做这个算法呢？
It's another one minute question.
这是另一个一分钟的问题。
So I guess I'm cheating.
所以我想我在作弊。
I'm taking time away.
我要抽时间。
Sorry.
抱歉。
So what if I would be finding a 1D
那如果我要找到一维
peak instead of finding a maximum?
高峰而不是找到最大值？
I'm looking at the running time, because if the running time is
我正在查看运行时间，因为如果运行时间是
going to be the same, it's not even worth
会一样，甚至不值得
thinking if it's correct or not.
在考虑是否正确。
If it's a more complicated algorithm
如果是更复杂的算法
with the same running time, why care about it?
在相同的运行时间下，为什么要关心它？
So is the running time going to be better?
那么运行时间会更好吗？
OK.
好。
I heard a nod.
我听到了点头。
Why?
为什么？
AUDIENCE: Won't it be log m times log n?
听众：会不会是log m乘log n？
VICTOR COSTAN: All right.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So 1D peak is exactly what we have there.
因此，一维峰正是我们所拥有的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
1D peak is exactly like you said, log m.
一维峰与您所说的完全相同，请记录m。
So this constant here becomes this constant here,
所以这里的这个常数变成这里的这个常数，
so the algorithm would be a lot faster.
所以算法会快很多。
As an order of magnitude idea, if your m and n are one million
作为一个数量级的想法，如果您的m和n为一百万
each, then log n is 20.
每个，则登录n为20。
So that's a 50 time max improvement.
因此，最多可提高50倍。
And these are real input sizes you might get.
这些是您可能会得到的实际输入大小。
And that's it.
就是这样。
Thank you guys.
感谢大伙们。